Embardo Collection of Lieberman V. Gant
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Embardo Collection of Lieberman v. Gant.
undated, 1973-1984
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Embardo, Ellen E.
.5 linear feet
In 1973, Marcia R. Lieberman was denied tenure with the University of Connecticut English Department. The same year, she initiated a class action suit against the institution, charging sexual discrimination on behalf of all women who had served or sought employment on or after 1 October 1967. The six year suit was found in favor of the University; Lieberman's appeal was denied in 1980. Ellen Embardo is a library staff member and one of the plaintiffs in the class action suit.
MSS19900045
Biography
In 1973, Marcia Lieberman was denied tenure with the University of Connecticut English Department. The same year, she initiated a class action suit against the institution, charging sexual discrimination on behalf of all women who had served or sought employment on or after 1 October 1967. The six-year suit was found in favor of the University; Lieberman's appeal was denied in 1980.
Scope and Content
The small collection contains correspondence, deposition copies, meeting minutes, newsletters, newspaper clippings, and other materials collected by one of the eighteen plaintiffs in the class action suit.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Lieberman, Marcia, 1936- —Trials, litigation, etc.; University of Connecticut.—Trials and litigation, etc.; Sex discrimination in higher education—Connecticut.; Sex discrimination against women—Connecticut.; Women in education—Trials, litigation, etc.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Legal Records.; Financial Records.; Lawsuits.
Occupations:
Librarian.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Ms. Embardo transferred her collection to the University Archives in 1990.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Collection, undated, 1973-1984
  - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Lawyer Fees, 1981-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Legal Documents, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Legal Documents, undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Legal Documents, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Library Personnel Procedures and Affirmative Action, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1982-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper and Journal Clippings, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 10)